[Music]
So, if you follow me on Instagram, you
know that I ate this entire tub last
week. It was really, really nice. Super
acidic flavor, which I know some people
don't like, but it was surprisingly good
ice cream. Had a really nice kind of
graham cracker swirl through it, but it
did miss a trick with the meringue part
key lime pie. But anyway, I want to
remake this. Uh this is last week I did
a review on the icy treat using this
generalized recipe, but this week I
wanted to go into more detail on this
recipe. So you can make it in any
machine you want to make. So let's
describe this ice cream. It says sweet
and tangy key lime ice cream with
ripples of buttery graham crumble. So
lemon lime ice cream with graham cracker
crumble. Now, I'm going to do that, but
I'm also going to have a meringue
element to it. So, we're going to do a
Swiss mering swirl to it, which Swiss
meringue is the kind of the same thing
that goes into Ben & Jerry's fish food.
Same kind of thing that's not it's
always sold as marshmallow, but it's
actually made as a Swiss mering. So,
that's what we're going to do today.
What are we going to need for our key
lime base?
So, for this recipe, you're going to
need 415 gram of 2% milk or whole milk,
370 g of whipping cream, 33% or higher.
In the UK, just use double cream. You're
going to need 130 g of straight sugar.
You're going to need 30 g of corn
syrup. I don't recommend using golden
syrup for this. just use corn syrup or
glucose
syrup. You're going to need 60 g of skim
milk powder, 2 g of stabilizer if you
decide to use it, and we're going to add
key lime extract at 5 to 7 g. So, that's
what it is. I'm actually going to make a
bigger batch, but that will give you
about a liter of base. So, let's get
everything weighed out and going.
415 g of
milk, 370 g of
cream, 130 g of alulose, 30 g of corn
syrup or glucose syrup, and I'm going to
use a stabilizer. So, I'm going to add
my milk powder into a little container,
which is 60 g. I'm going to use a
stabilizer. For those eagle-eyed folks,
I am making a doublesized batch. Stir
that in. If you don't use a stabilizer,
don't worry about
it. And our milk powder goes into here.
And we're going to stir
this. Because I'm using a stabilizer,
I'm going to heat this up on hob to 80
to 85 C,
185. And that's going to activate my
stabilizer. If you don't use a
stabilizer, just heat it up to about 50
60° C, which is this in Fahrenheit, to
make sure all your ingredients are fully
homogenated and blended together. So,
I'm going to do that and then I'll bring
it back. Right, so we are heated up and
I've just let it cool down for a few
minutes. That will just bring the
temperature down by about 10° pretty
quickly and that's because I'm going to
put in my extract. Always best to let it
cool down slightly to put in extracts.
Some, man, that's
strong. Some uh can kind of separate on
the top if you put it in too hot. It
will incorporate once it cools down
again, so don't kind of stress about it
too much. But what we're going to do is
we're going to put
in five
g. It's pretty strong, and that's
because this was a really strong
flavor.
Let's say that's about
right. We'll just dribble it all down
the side and then don't worry about
it. Lauran do some really strong oils.
Now I I was recommended by a channel
supporter Mark. Hi Mark. To use a very
specific type of extract for a true
natural flavor. It is available. It's
just going to take ages to get it here.
So, if you want to make this, I'm going
to put a link in the description
of what I would use if you really want
to go down the super good flavor route.
This, let's see how this one turns out.
It smells really nice. So, with your
base heated up, you can put it in a
container, get that chilling down in the
fridge overnight. Let that let that lime
flavor build. We want this to be pretty
strong on flavorful. It's quite acidic.
I'm going to try and keep an eye on what
happens to it. There is the chance that
this will kind of separate slightly. So,
let's keep an eye and see what it does.
So, whilst the ice cream is chilling in
the fridge, we're going to make our
graham cracker crumb swirl blocks
pieces, cubes, stuff. Um, this is pretty
easy. What we're going to do is we're
going to turn the oven on to
375F and get everything together. So,
you're simply going to need a pretty
plain old bowl. Could be anything you
like. Doesn't need to be a bowl. If
you're making one liter of ice cream,
you are going to need 100 g of graham
cracker crumb, 50 g of melted butter,
and 20 g of corn syrup, glucose or
golden syrup. That corn syrup and golden
syrup really is quite essential to
create that harder, chewier graham
cracker crumb. Without it, it kind of
just separates into a million pieces.
You can add more butter, but the butter
starts leeching out of it. Let's start
with our graham cracker in the bowl. I
mean, in reality, you could have just
melted the butter in there first and
added it in after, but I like doing
things the awkward
way. There's 100 g of butter. We're
going to melt this in the microwave.
Make sure there's no lumps left in
there. Let's get that into
here. It's quite a lot of butter because
we really want that buttery flavor.
Graham cracker is quite a buttery flavor
anyway, but adding this butter really
gives you a texture that is just amazing
as an addin in ice cream. So, we've got
that and our final ingredient, which is
our corn syrup, which is 10 g. We got a
little bit of residual heat left from
that
butter. And that's kind of coating
everything as well. That corn syrup, if
you want to use glucose syrup, use that.
If you want to use golden syrup, that
works incredibly well cuz it really
brings out the caramel notes and graham
cracker as well. Baking pan. Let's line
them with some parchment. And we are
just going to load this up. Leave
yourself a little bit of excess of
parchment. Just so you can fold it
over like so. We are going to wait for
the oven to come up to temperature. Then
we're going to pop it in for about 5 to
8 minutes depending on your oven. We
don't want to burn this. We just want to
cook that butter and sugar together and
that will bond and form a cohesive mix
that will hold everything together. So
once it's cooked 5 to 8 minutes, take it
out and let it cool down to room
temperature. Then cool it down in the
fridge for a couple of hours. And you're
going to chop it up into whatever size
pieces you want. I like to go for kind
of centime squares, something like that,
and put them in a container. Store them
in the fridge until ready to use. What
I'm doing is I'm just cleaning this
metal bowl. This is the smallest metal
bowl I have. We're going to do our
meringue top. So, key lime pie
traditionally comes with either meringue
served on top or whipped cream. So, so
in here we've just got an inch of water.
We've got this warming up and we just
want to get this to a simmer. We don't
want it boiling away. And we also don't
need a lot in there, okay? Cuz we're
just going to transfer heat into this
bowl specifically to melt the sugar in
our egg whites. Swiss meringue is the
best meringue to use for ice cream. add
in. It gives you a result similar to
marshmallow fluff. French meringue is
whipping egg whites with sugar in the
hope that the sugar dissolves and
creates a pillowy result. It's a very
traditional way of making it. Your
Italian meringue is heating up your
sugars and usually water, small amount
of water anyway, uh until it dissolves
and gets up to the candy stages. So,
softball and hard ball stages. Then you
start adding that hot melted sugar into
your whipping egg whites and that will
start to cook your egg whites and create
a nice result. It's delicious. Italian
meringue. Swiss meringue is the easier
version of Italian meringue. Egg whites
with sugar and you warm that up enough
to dissolve the sugar and then you just
whip it in in a machine or by hand. I'm
going to do it by hand because I got so
many machines here in this video I don't
need anymore.
So, with our water boiling, we're going
to put our egg white in. Now, there
seems to be some information online,
which is false, about you cannot use
storebought egg whites to make mering.
You absolutely can. That's
rubbish. The proteins are more stable in
fresh eggs for sure, and it is easier to
whip that way. But I'm going to show you
now that you can absolutely, these are
from Walmart. You absolutely can use
these straight storebought egg whites.
What you need to do is just to add a
stabilizer. And in this instance, we're
going to add cream of tarta here
available everywhere. Um, you can use uh
lemon juice. You're looking for an acid
to stabilize the egg whites and you're
also looking for the combination of
starch. The creamarta is is it's kind of
like an acidic starch where it does
everything needed. You can use things
like guarantham to stabilize egg whites.
It's not particularly good because it
doesn't melt properly and you need to
make sure it's incorporated into your
liquid. But for now, the standard way is
cream of tarta. One one egg whites to
sugar. That's the number. One. A large
egg white is about 40 to 50 g in weight.
So 40 to 50 g of weight, 40 to 50 g of
sugar. No matter how many egg whites you
use, same amount of weight in sugar for
Swiss mering. That is important because
you want it to be stable and you want it
to be stable in our ice cream. So, let's
get that weighed out. So, 150 g of
storebought egg white. Into that
goes 150 g of
sugar. In goes wherever it is our cream
fittata. And we're going to put
in, if I can get the lid open, we're
going to put
in a/3 of a teaspoon. Let's simply
combine all these together and put it on
there. Get a spatula as well because as
this starts heating up, we want to make
sure those sugar crystals, let me show
you what I'm talking about. These sugar
crystals on the
side come off. We want all of that to be
incorporated into our meringue.
Otherwise, we're going to have crunchy
bits of sugar and that's no good. So,
with the meringue or the sugar dissolved
properly, what we're going to do now is
whisk it up. I do recommend that you use
a stand mixer for this cuz it's a pretty
hardgoing process to do it by hand. So,
get your stand mixer and whisk this up.
And you're whisking it up until the
temperature comes down. You need to
bring that temperature almost back down
to room temperature. When it is, you can
then add in your vanilla extract. This
is just homemade vanilla extract, but
use whatever vanilla flavor you want.
Stir it in because now we are going to
start getting our ice cream base which
is completely chilled in the fridge into
our machine. Towards the end of your
churn, you're going to start adding in
your cubes of graham cracker crumb. Then
when it's load up time, you can then
take a nice big spoonful of ice cream,
put it in your container, and then a
nice layer of your marshmallow cream.
And then load it back up the whole tub.
Doing this, alternating. And then
finally going to put it in the freezer
for a good few hours to harden off. And
then you know what? It's time to eat
some. Scoops beautifully. Really nice
texture. Let's have a
look. Oh man, that looks good. That
really, really does look good. I'm I'm
super looking forward to trying this
one. So, let's see what it's like.
I am excited to try the churned version
of this with everything
in that is
amazing. I knew the flavor was good
because obviously at the same time I was
doing this I did the uh review for the
Icy Tree ice cream maker. So having that
ice cream through those three different
spinning machines gave me the indication
that the flavor was good. Anyway, but
obviously in a CH machine, you get the
air. So, it's not as intensely cold. The
air insulate is insulated and creates a
slightly warmer mouth feel to your ice
cream. So, it's a much more decadent
kind of experience when you use uh an
ice cream churning machine. So, a
traditional ice cream machine. But here
we've got that Swiss meringue folded in.
It gives you that incredibly nice
marshmallow kind of texture. The vanilla
of that Swiss mering coming through with
the chewy pieces of that graham cracker
crust. Everything about this is
perfect. The ice cream is a glorious
texture. Lovely, lovely lime flavor.
That extract, Lauran extract is really
nice. When the other one turns up that
was recommended, I will try that again
cuz I I want to look deeper
into flavors and how extracts are made.
But this ice cream is incredible. Top 10
ice cream this one. This is an absolute
winner. Anyway, thanks very much to
Hogenaz for the inspiration. We've taken
your 6 out of 10 ice cream and turned it
into a 10 out of 10 ice cream that you
can make at home. Don't forget to like
and subscribe and I will see you next
week. Seriously good.
[Music]